cottagesmallholder.com 2013-11-29

# Privacy Policy | The Cottage Smallholder

**PRIVACY POLICY for www.CottageSmallholder.com**

This page explains our policy regarding your privacy when visiting our site or communicating electronically with us. It explains what happens to any personal data that you provide to us, and to any non-personal data we collect when you are on this site.

We update this Policy from time to time so please do return and review it occasionally.

**Information We Collect**

In operating our website we may collect and process the following data about you:

  1. Details of your visits to our website and the resources that you access, including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data. All web sites have this capability.
  2. Personal information that you provide by filling in forms on our website, such as when you register or leave a comment on the blog or forum
  3. Information provided to us when you communicate with us for any reason.

We may on occasion gather information regarding your computer whilst you are on our website.

Such information does not identify you personally. It is statistical data about our visitors and their use of our site. This statistical data does not identify any personal details whatsoever.

This enables us to improve our services and to provide statistical information regarding the use of our website to our advertisers where appropriate.

**Use of Cookies**

A cookie is an alphanumeric identifier which we transfer to your hard drive through your web browser when you visit our website. It enables our own system to recognise you when you visit our website again and improve our service to you. Cookies may also be used to compile aggregate information about areas of our website that are visited most frequently. This traffic information can be used to enhance the content of our website and make your use of it easier.

Our advertisers may also use cookies, over which we have no control.  Such cookies (if used) would be downloaded once you click on advertisements on our website.

All computers have the ability to decline cookies.  This can be done by activating the setting on your browser which enables you to decline the cookies. Please note that should you choose to decline cookies, you may be unable to access particular parts of our website.

**Use of Your Information**

The information that we collect and store relating to you is primarily used to enable us to provide our services to you.

We do not send unsolicited emails to registered users or visitors who have left comments on the blog or forum. The sole exception may be an occasional seasonal electronic greeting card sent to regular contributors of the site.

We never reveal your personal data to third parties unless legally forced to do so by a court or government agency.

We do not reveal any information whatsoever about identifiable individuals to our advertisers but we may, on occasion, provide them with aggregate statistical information about our visitors.

**Storing Your Personal Data**

All personal data is stored and processed within the European Economic Area. Our server is located in the UK. We will take all reasonable steps to make sure that your personal data is treated securely and in agreement with this Privacy Policy.

The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of data sent to us electronically and transmission of such data is therefore entirely at your own risk. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password so that you can access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.

**Third[Party](http://www.cottagesmallholder.com/party-8147/) Links**

There are links on our website to third party websites. These websites should have their own privacy policies which you may check. We do not accept any responsibility or liability whatsoever for their policies as we have no control over them.

**Ad Servers**

To try and bring you offers that are of interest to you, we have relationships with other companies that we allow to place ads on our Web pages. As a result of your visit to our site, ad server companies may collect information such as your domain type, your IP address and clickstream information.

**Access To Information**

The Data Protection Act 1998 gives you the right to access the information that we hold about you. Be assured that the only personal data we hold about you is what you have submitted to us. Please note that any demand for access may be subject to payment of a fee of £10 which covers our costs in providing you with the information requested.  Should you wish to receive details that we hold about you please contact us using the contact details below.

**Contacting Us**

We welcome any queries, comments or requests you may have regarding this Privacy Policy.  Please do not hesitate to contact us by using the “Contact us” form accessible from the button/tab at the top of this screen, or by email to:

Fiona [at] cottagesmallholder [dot] com.
